

MANOHAR PALANISAMY

Date of birth: 15/03/1995

Nationality: Indian

Gender: Male

CONTACT

Salem, India

send2manoo@gmail.com

(+91) 9819876078

http://bit.ly/MLNotesStanford

http://bit.ly/ ManoharPalanisamy

LinkedIn: http://bit.ly/

ManoharPalanisamyLinkedIn

Other: http://bit.ly/
GithubManohar



ABOUT ME

I'm learned from failure, self-taught, independent, motivated and passionate about technology. I gathered knowledge from basic to advanced in Big Data, Parallel Computing, Machine learning, Neural Networks and Computer Vision. It is easy to grasp a term in Artificial Intelligence. I did plenty of projects in real time. It made me proud being a researcher; I like two words from English, Discipline and Confidence. This is what I always believe to reach the goal. I understand every bit and byte of a computer. Like, English to machine language zero's and One's feeding the logic gates of the computer transistors.

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

05/09/2012 - 25/04/2016 - India

Computer Science and Engineering

Anna University

02/07/2010 - 22/05/2012 - India

Mathematics and Computer Science

Higher Secondary Course Certificate

WORK EXPERIENCE

31/01/2017 - 21/11/2018 - Mumbai, India

Software Developer Executive

QuantumLink Communications Pvt Ltd

- I was responsible for handling feature enhancement and bug fixing related to our products which also included understanding the requirements and preparing design documents and Impact Analysis. I used Core Java, JavaScript, Spring, Jquery, Servlet, Freemarker, HTML, Ajax, CSS and MySQL.
- Developing a Research-based web application FieldSense. This
 project is based on a Salesforce tracking system which is used to
 track a salesperson and worked as an email product that has
 complete knowledge of network and email protocols to Ensured
 timely delivery and quality all compliant with the client's quality
 processes.

Information and communication

02/03/2016 - 07/04/2016 - Salem, India

Trainee Developer Intern

Vetri Systems

- I worked on a project titled "MEDI SOFT CLOUD BASED MOBILE APPLICATION FOR HEALTH CARE SERVICES". This project was aimed to Automation solution that goes well beyond just field and sales force tracking. The MEDI SOFT mobile app allows your field and sales force to perform a range of routine activities like reaching meeting destinations with real-time navigation assistance.
- I used java micro architecture to create the applications and bootstrap used for the adaptability of the application to all mobile devices.

CERTIFICATIONS

07/02/2017 - 05/02/2022

Machine Learning

An online course authorized by Stanford University and offered through Coursera

https://coursera.org/verify/WFUWAE7JQ924

15/05/2019 - 21/01/2022

Applied AI with DeepLearning

An online course authorized by IBM and offered through Coursera coursera.org/verify/DRENBUK43NW8

27/01/2017 - 04/12/2018

Deep Learning and Computer Vision

This certificate above verifies that Manohar Palanisamy successfully completed the course Deep Learning and Computer Vision A-Z™: OpenCV, SSD & GANs on 12/04/2018 as taught by Hadelin de Ponteves, Kirill Eremenko, Ligency I Team, Ligency Team on Udemy.

https://udemy-certificate.s3.amazonaws.com/image/UC-UEOKI4W6.jpg

27/05/2016 - 08/08/2016

Advanced Java Programming

This certificate above verifies that Manohar Palanisamy successfully completed the course Advanced Java Programming on 08/08/2016 as taught by Infinite Skills on Udemy.

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-UO2X33A1/

20/11/2015 - 07/08/2016

Java Multithreading

https://www.udemy.com/certificate/UC-X0ZFJXQ9/

02/07/2014 - 08/10/2014

C and C++ Programming

CREATIVE WORKS

17/07/2020 - CURRENT

Marvel Image Classifier

 Transfer learning using Resnet50 Architecture from Fast Al Library (Marvel Heroes Classification) to classify Marvel Heroes based on 12 Classes (Super Heroes)

http://bit.ly/MarvelHeroesClassification

07/10/2020 - CURRENT

Machine Learning Notes

 Developing Machine learning Notes for my reference and wrote some difficult topics on layman terms. which were inspired by Andrew NG, Computer Scientist.

http://bit.ly/MLNotesStanford

PROJECTS

02/05/2018 - 07/06/2018

Distributed Deep Learning | Horovod | Message Passing Interface(MPI)

https://github.com/send2manoo/Distributed-Deep-Learning-With-Horovod-MPI

- Horovod is a distributed training framework for Keras and TensorFlow. The goal of Horovod is to make distributed Deep Learning fast and easy to use.
- The primary motivation for this project is to make it easy to take a single-GPU TensorFlow program and successfully train it on many GPUs faster.

03/03/2018 - 25/03/2018

Image Augmentation Model | Convolutional Neural Network(CNN)

https://github.com/send2manoo/Image-Classification

- Automate extraction of Screen shots from Photos.
- I've trained a CNN model to predict Screen Shot files from Album and extract them out of photos directory.

05/11/2018 - CURRENT

Object Detection Using Single-Shot Detection(SSD)

 Worked on Open Source SSD model Using VOC dataset to detect the object in Videos and Photos.

07/09/2017 - 15/09/2017

Spark | Distributed cluster | scala | pyspark

https://github.com/send2manoo/Spark-Example

- Implement Word Count project using Scala and Build with SBT and run spark jobs across HDFS clusters with the help of YARN.
- Develop spark programmes using pyspark as per the requirement.

HONOURS AND AWARDS

07/03/2014

Code Debugging – TECHMEET-2014
First Prize for Code Debugging in TECHMEET-2014 in our college

DIGITAL SKILLS

Docker Container / BIG DATA Knowledge / MACHINE LEARNING / Al and Deep Neural Networks / Computer Vision Basics / Derivatives / Gradient Descent / Natural Languages Proccessing / Data structures / Web Programming: HTML, CSS, Javascript (front-end), Java (back-end) / programming software engineering software development / Deployment of web servers running IIS, Apache, NGINX / Machine Learning (Andrew Ng course on Coursera) / Algorithm Design / Artificial Intelligence and Machine Learning concepts

LANGUAGE SKILLS

OTHER LANGUAGE(S):

English

Listening	Reading	Spoken	Spoken	Writing
B2	B2	production	interaction	B2
		B2	B2	